He's facing the ultimate challenge. And fighting for his life.
Rocky IV is a drama film directed by Sylvester Stallone.
Rocky Balboa holds the world heavyweight championship, but a new challenger has stepped forward:
Drago, a six-foot-four, 261-pound fighter who has the backing of the Soviet Union.
This time, Rocky's training regimen takes him to Siberia, where he
prepares for a globally televised match in the heart of Moscow.
But nothing can truly prepare him for what he's about to face – a fight to the finish, in
which he must defend not only himself, but also the honor of his country!
Robert "Rocky" Balboa, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Ivan Drago, played by Dolph Lundgren.
Apollo Creed, played by Carl Weathers.
Adrianna "Adrian" Balboa, played by Talia Shire.
Paulie Pennino, played by Burt Young.
Ludmilla Vobet Drago, played by Brigitte Nielsen.
Rocky IV is a 1985 American sports drama film starring,
written and directed by Sylvester Stallone.
The film is the sequel to Rocky III (1982) and the
fourth installment in the Rocky franchise.
It also stars Talia Shire, Burt Young, Carl Weathers,
Brigitte Nielsen, and Dolph Lundgren.
In the film, Rocky Balboa (Stallone) confronts Ivan Drago (Lundgren), a Soviet
boxer responsible for another personal tragedy in Balboa's life.
Development for a fourth Rocky film began soon after the success of Rocky III.
Principal photography began in 1984, with filming locations
including Philadelphia, Wyoming, and Vancouver.
Rocky IV was Lundgren's American film debut, and Stallone's last directorial effort until Rocky Balboa in 2006; they
engaged in authentic punching in their fight scenes, which led to Stallone being admitted to intensive care.
Filming also featured new special effects and bona fide, groundbreaking sport
methods and equipment, some of which were years removed from public use.
Rocky IV is known for its strong Cold War themes, as well as its successful theme
songs "Burning Heart" by Survivor and "Living in America" by James Brown.
Rocky IV premiered in Los Angeles on November 21, 1985, and was theatrically
released in the United States by MGM/UA Entertainment Co.
under its United Artists label on November 27.
The film initially received mixed reviews, with praise for Drago's
credibility as a villain, but criticized the predictable screenplay.
Scholars note that Drago's ultimate defeat and the Soviet crowd's embrace of Rocky represented the dissolution of the Soviet
Union, while others criticized the film as propaganda through its Cold War themes and negative portrayals of Russians.
Rocky IV grossed $300.5 million worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing Rocky film, the
third-highest-grossing US film of 1985 and the second-highest-grossing film worldwide.
Later reviews were more favorable in the years later,
with praise for the training montages.
The film is considered an icon of 1980s pop
culture, and gained a cult following.
In 2021, a director's cut was released with the title Rocky IV: Rocky vs
Drago – The Ultimate Director's Cut, receiving positive reviews.
A sequel, Rocky V, was released in 1990.
The film's storylines are continued in Creed II (2018),
part of the sequel series to the Rocky films.
The film explores themes of dying and death, friendship,
transporter, sports, loss of loved one.
The tone is emotional.